so when I was in my third year of
University I was seen double four weeks
I was in my courses these big like 300
people courses like what I try to see
the board a friend and eventually I went
to my family doctor when I googled the
symptoms in my laboratory
it said brain tumor and it's like I
might have a brain tumor and I went to
my doctor and she diagnosed you with
dehydration and I came back feeling
silly it is deadly if it's not treated
but drink Gatorade for a few weeks and
it didn't go away and so I finally went
to the emergency room and basically made
them give me a cat scan they acted like
I was ripping off the system I'm
ridiculous I'm a 25 year old of course
you know like what could it be
but another doctor had told me if I felt
nauseous I needed to go in and get a cat
scan so I was like no he said I'm here
give me the cat scan and they did under
duress and came back that I had a brain
tumor
they were like how's your hearing I
didn't even know I had trouble hearing I
had lost I only have 30% of hearing left
in the ear that it was affecting so I
spent it was about two months between
being diagnosed and going under the
knife having my actual surgery which is
like a 12-hour process it was a very
profound experience getting diagnosed
with brain tumors
both because of the community support
the amount of like my friends in the
laboratory and in school and my old
friends from Starbucks who like
surrounded me with love and connection
and came to visit me in the hospital
after it and invited me out to do things
and I was more likely to say yes and go
out and do things cuz I didn't know I
mean when you're 25 to hear you're
having brain surgery you think death or
permanent dismemberment and like the
worst thing I could think of was losing
my hair and not being able to smile and
having half my face not work which is
one of the common symptoms having had
this surgery it's an acoustic neuroma
and so then coming out of the surgery I
was deaf in one ear my double vision
redirected itself the other way so I had
worse television after but my
brain was relearning how to fill in
those holes so it wasn't gonna stay that
way I had to relearn balance but it got
worse because my brain as well they took
me off of steroids and I ended up acting
like a two-year-old which becoming a
parent gave me a lot of insight but at
the time it really was hard it was hard
to feel like the world is attacking me
with light and sound and yet I can't
even communicate my needs and people
needing meeting communicate my needs
repeatedly the doctors both that they
took me off the steroids when they
weren't supposed to even though it made
sense medically but also going to my
family doctor in a state of my brain
swell you know her not recognizing it
just kind of calling and getting new
steroids are not new to steroids new
painkillers and so there were extra days
that I had my brain swelling and damaged
I had to be readmitted to the hospital I
had a spinal tap I ended up staying with
my my boss from the laboratory my dad
came in and he had to take time off of
work and come and watch me during the
day while she was at work I like
couldn't I'm never walking typical vote
that's how that's how much I vote in
every election well I could barely walk
and had to it was it was a hard time
we're learning how to have a new brain
and this was actually just sensory stuff
it was just having they could not be
able to walk and be not you know what
tell direction of sound and not being
able to counsel Oh background noise and
how much of a drastic impact that had on
my life going to parties and not being
able to council it out and being so
exhausted the end of everyday even
without a lot of background noise just
feeling tired extremely tired but the
university accommodated my my needs
while I was in the process of getting
getting brain tumors and I had an extra
like you're a tomb about five years to
the four years to four year degree
excite yeah that's an economics class
that I took the final later and I had
some other courses that I didn't finish
and I was kind of allowed to do some
coursework and not other course work and
those brain tumors changed my life
then that was in 2005 when I was 25 then
in 2010 the brain tumors grew back and
we're growing back and so I could keep
getting surgery which is like 12 hours
long or I could get radiation and I
really didn't want to have radiation but
it was the only option and as much as
the brain swelling changed my brain
radiation changed it so much more I when
you go through radiation you're expected
to have symptoms but they're supposed to
go away and my never really did I became
very sensitive to smells and it has
stayed I was nauseous constantly and my
brain still continues to change to this
day it's not medically explainable
supposedly after you've had brain to
brain radiated radiation on your brain
which lets just get better and you're
fine
and fine didn't seem to I'm at an
increased risk for strokes I I'm not
able to learn things in the same way I
did before that all happened so in
between those in that five years I
graduated from University I worked at
Vancity for a while and learned finance
went to school actually to take
financial planning and did well in that
became a government worker was the top
of my class could understand that stuff
no problem then I went underwent
radiation and I had to do level two and
I just like couldn't get it I couldn't
understand I can't read and retain
information the same way and well they
did the preliminary work for the
radiation they found I had another tumor
at the top of my head and this is part
of my reading into things baby but I was
like okay so I'm not listening I'm not
listening I got a tumor on my hearing
nerve in my listening and that I didn't
I didn't listen to whatever lesson the
life was there to teach me and so it
gave me like a second one on my crown
chakra that was like you're not
listening Oh to your higher power you're
not listening to your higher power and
so I had surgery in 2010 no sorry I
surgery in 2005 radiation in 2010 and
then another surgery in 2015 my daughter
was already alive she was two and a half
my mom had to come and watch her and I
just rest being her because I was going
to
medication and it was and now that it's
20/20 I'm like okay this is the year I'm
not gonna have brain done not that
brain and so that's my brain tumor
story which isn't quite the changing of
my brain which is my neurodiversity and
I'm going to do a second video one point
to explain that in particular but brain
tumors they have been a really hard part
of my life and like every piece of the
story I wouldn't change it for the world
because it's led me exactly where I am
and exactly what I'm here to do